# DAN ROM

danrom2210@gmail.com +27 (079) 034 4465

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am currently in my final year at the University of Cape Town studying towards a degree in Electrical and Computer Engineering. My passion for the content I am learning allows me to excel in my studies. I have a friendly and outgoing personality and am able to cope well in high-stress situations. To view projects I have worked on throughout my studies, both part of and external to the university curriculum, please view my portfolio

## **EDUCATION**

## University of Cape Town

March 2021 - Present

Studying towards a Bachelor of Science in Engineering in Electrical and Computer Engineering Faculty of Engineering and the Built Environment

# King David Victory Park High School

2016-2020

IEB National Senior Certificate

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## Freelance Tutor

January 2021 - November 2023

Made use of Zoom online platform to provide support for students in Grade 7 - Grade 12 in: Accounting, Afrikaans, Hebrew, Information Technology, Mathematics and Physical Science

#### Think Camp Coding Tutor

September 2022 - February 2024

Facilitated multiple classes of 3-6 students at a time, taking them through the Think Camp coding syllabus. Students' ages range between 9 and 16 and languages taught include Scratch, LiveCode and Python.

#### Synthesis Student Intern

December 2023

Took part in the Synthesis Vacation Work program. My project involved building a full scale application for internal office use - making use of React JS for the front end and Python for the back end.

#### **Innovation Labs Tutor**

July 2024 - Present

As a tutor for Innovation Labs, I was involved in the running of a weekly extra-curricular activity at Reddam House Constantia High School where students are able to learn the fundamentals of Electrical Engineering. This includes basic circuit theory, an introduction to microcontrollers as well as practical projects where the students could use their knowledge to build a working project - often involving integrating a sensor with a microcontroller.

## Signals and Systems Tutor

July 2024 - October 2024

In the final year of my undergraduate degree, I was employed as a tutor for the second year Signals and Systems (EEE2047S). Responsibilities included running tutorial sessions for the students, assisting in any questions they had regarding the course content. I also assisted in the marking of tests, labs and assignments.

#### ACADEMIC AWARDS

# University Awards

· Included in Dean's Merit List, 2021, 2022 and 2023.

#### **High School Awards**

- · Graduated Summa Cum Laude (average over 90 percent) with 9 distinctions from King David Victory Park High School, 2020.
- · Ranked in the top 1 percent of IEB students in the English Home Language final examination, 2020.

## LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

- · Treasurer of the South African Union of Jewish Students (SAUJS) Western Cape, 2022-2023
- · Head Boy of King David Victory Park High School, 2019-2020.
- · Chosen to represent King David Victory Park on the **Johannesburg Junior Council**, 2018-2019.

## **SKILLS**

# Programming Skills:

Experience in Python, Java, Embedded C, C++, MATLAB and React JS.

## **Public Speaking:**

Member of the winning team out of 108 schools in the 'Speech and Drama College High School Public Speaking Festival' in the Impromptu section (2019)

## Languages:

Fluent in English, intermediate proficiency in Afrikaans and Hebrew